It's quite lively at the Ye Residence now.
Why are you out here alone?
They're having fun,
but it has nothing much to do with me.
Do you want to drink?
What do you mean?
To help you find the courage
to talk to me.
I'm afraid you'll stand up
and leave mid-sentence.
Even if I do stand up and leave,
can't you finish my sentence?
Duke Su, how did you investigate
your cases in the past?
Don't always make me put up an act
before you make a confession.
In the interrogation chambers
of Duke Mansion,
you didn't get to interrogate me.
You can do it today.
You have a sharp memory.
Ask me anything.
No one tells the truth
without a little pressure.
If that's the case,
will you be accusing me
of threatening a noble lady in the future?
You can argue with me any day,
but can you be lenient with me today?
What's your surname?
Ask me another question.
- No, this is my rule.
- I don't have a surname then.
- What's your name?
- I have no name.
Where are you from?
I'm a restless spirit
from the Qingcheng Mountain.
I am not Jiang Li.
I know.
You are just
a little civet.
I've known you for so long
and you're still so unserious.
That makes me more annoying, right?
Duke Su,
you really
are eccentric.
I don't care what people think about me
or how they criticize me.
Annoying people live long.
Smile.
You took Tong Zhiyang down.
You should smile.
I'll treat you to steamed buns today.
The wrapper is white and fluffy
with a fresh and tender filling.
Mouthwatering with a delicious aroma.
Duke Su,
do you think people only cherish
the things that they have lost?
Only fools do that.
I'm probably a fool then.
The moon is so beautiful tonight.
You are not a fool.
You never trampled on someone's life.
No matter how many regrets you have now,
you're worthy of your past and future.
That's why you dared to return
and find out what happened
then move forward to seek justice.
Suddenly being all serious
makes you look pretentious.
It doesn't matter.
After today,
I'm once again despised by everyone.
The city of Luyang is so nice.
But it's late. The night duty is coming.
Go home then.
That's not my home.
Li.
For prisoners,
it's important to verify identity.
But humans don't need
to seek clarity in everything.
The lights are on in Luyang now.
If you were a restless spirit,
you would've long been reduced to ashes.
I will live on well.
YE RESIDENCE
You're so handsome.
Duke Su,
do you think people only cherish
the things that they have lost?
For prisoners,
it's important to verify identity.
But humans don't need
to seek clarity in everything.
The lights are on in Luyang now.
If you were a restless spirit,
you would've long been reduced to ashes.
Home?
I no longer have a home.
Miss, the servant just sent a message.
A woman would like you to visit her home.
- Who is it?
- Qiong Zhi.
Qiong Zhi?
- It's the blusher shop in the south.
- Really?
It looks good.
This color is nice.
That color is particularly pretty.
I must try it then.
- It's almost done drying, right?
- Are you here to see Ms. Qiong Zhi?
Yes.
Her medicine is cooking.
Let her drink it later.
May I ask what disease
Qiong Zhi is down with?
Tong'er, wait for me here.
Qiong Zhi.
Ms. Jiang.
The water is over there.
Help yourself.
What happened to you?
I wanted to find you as soon as possible.
I didn't expect
that I couldn't get up.
Is there any news?
Ms. Jiang, you're a person of nobility,
but you are not from the Xue family.
Knowing so many things
is all just entertainment for you.
Without the word nobility,
if it is as you said
that I see human life as entertainment,
then I shouldn't even be a person.
Why bother?
This murder case happened long ago.
When the gavel came down,
those who should die
and those who shouldn't were all dead.
Should this case be overturned,
all the dark and filthy will resurface.
Your luxurious clothing
will get dirty too.
In this world,
there has to be someone who dares
to return and find out what happened,
then move forward to seek justice.
Magistrate Xue
is not dead.
Really?
A few days ago,
some officials from Huaixiang
came to Xihua Brothel.
Cui Zhu? Where is Cui Zhu?
- Magistrate Feng.
- Cui Zhu.
Magistrate Feng, you're late.
Well…
- Let Cui Zhu come out.
- Cui Zhu…
Cui Zhu is feeling unwell today.
We have three new ladies here.
They are all pretty good.
Ning Lian, Yu'er, hurry.
- Coming!
- Magistrate Feng. Come.
Get away from me.
We only want Cui Zhu today.
- These people already came once before.
- Cui Zhu!
Cui Zhu hosted them.
They paid handsomely,
but…
According to Cui Zhu,
as those three were drunk,
they…
What are you doing?
What are you doing? Let me go.
Let go!
Cui Zhu, did you miss me?
Please don't, Magistrate Feng.
Let me go!
Please, Magistrate Feng.
- Let me go!
- Don't move.
I beg you.
Let me go!
No!
Cui Zhu.
Don't touch me!
It's me. Cui Zhu.
These animals.
- I'll report this to officials.
- Don't.
Don't, Qiong Zhi.
I still need this money
to treat my mother's illness.
Don't go.
Two days ago, those three came again.
Drink one more
Everyone didn't dare to host them.
The madam asked us to draw lots.
Just draw it. Think of it
as earning money for your family.
I'll go.
After Magistrate Xue was put on death row,
he wasn't executed immediately.
The execution is six months later.
But now, it's almost time
for his execution.
That was all I could get
from them.
It's all right.
It's just that my cheap life
wouldn't be able to wait
until the day justice is served.
That day will come.
You have to wait
and see for yourself
what ending awaits those men.
Qiong Zhi,
I will return to Huaixiang
to seek justice for you
and overturn the Xue family's case.
I want to personally capture
those lowly beasts,
peel their skin,
and drink their blood.
I swear to you.
Just wait.
You must live well.
The Xue family is fortunate
to have a friend like you.
Ms. Jiang,
do you remember the drawing in this box?
Xue Zhao is not an ignorant
and incompetent fool.
This drawing is not
some leisurely doodles.
It's just that I am not smart enough
to figure out what he left me.
ENTRANCE, TOP CAVE ENTRANCE,
MINING AREA
I'll leave Xue Zhao's last work
to you.
Solve it.
Wait, Qiong Zhi.
I'll get the physician.
Jiang Li,
I know my condition well.
When I first arrived at Xihua Brothel,
I sought death countless times,
but to no avail.
Now, I know
the heavens kept me alive…
to await your arrival.
Jiang Li,
you must remember what you promised.
Seek justice
for people like us.
All right. I'll get you your medicine.
Xue Zhao.
I'm coming to you.
ZHAO
Qiong Zhi.
Duke Su, I asked the house owner.
Chu Lan's rent is paid annually
in gold.
Gold bars?
If so, an investigation would be easier.
They're not gold bars
cast by the imperial court,
but scrap gold.
Payment in grains of gold?
There seems to be a gold mine around.
That can't be.
Due to land disasters in the south
two years ago,
the imperial court closed down all mines.
Luyang's mining ban has yet to be lifted.
There can't be any gold mines around.
The imperial mine is closed…
Private mines? My goodness.
Privately mining imperial gold mines
is as guilty as treason.
But we don't know where the mine is.
They can't hide it.
They won't have much manpower
and mines that can be accessed immediately
are mostly open-pit, sand gold mines.
Wen Ji,
look along the downstream
closed imperial mines.
Yes.
Jiang Li,
I picked out some fine satin for you.
Jiang Li!
Li'er, come eat some melon seeds.
Li'er!
Jiang Li, this pot of flowers
is as beautiful as you are.
I'll put it in your room.
Would you like that?
- Where is she?
Nothing serious happened, right?
She wouldn't do anything stupid
like you did last time, right?
Hang herself, bump into the wall,
or jump into a lake?
How scary.
This won't do.
We have to get someone to check on her.
Wait. Why are you all looking at me?
I'm not good with words.
I don't know how to comfort people.
Then let's do the usual. Draw lots.
Jiang Li, where are you going
with your luggage?
I have important things to do.
What exactly is it? Tell me.
Come on. What's happening to you?
Let me leave.
Hold on, Jiang Li.
Seeing you so distracted today,
I knew something had happened.
Tell me.
There is strength in numbers.
When I was at Zhennv Hall,
I met a young lady.
If not for her,
I wouldn't be alive.
Later on, she died of illness.
Before she died, she told me
her father used to be
the magistrate of Huaixiang.
He was framed and died
in an unpleasant way.
She was stuck in Zhennv Hall,
unable to hold her father's funeral.
She said that if I go back someday,
I must help her place some flowers
on her father's grave.
This way, both of them
can meet again in the next life.
Later on, I sent someone to ask around
and found out today
that her father is not dead.
Instead, he is imprisoned
in Huaixiang's prison.
Do you want to look
into her father's case?
Jia'er,
do you think I shouldn't meddle in this?
The Jiang Li I know wouldn't ask me
if she should or not.
She will stand up
for anything that is just.
Tell me when you are going.
I'll go with you.
I'll pack my things right away.
Jia'er, Uncle Mingxuan just came home.
You're still handling
the faltered business.
You have to stay here.
I'll go to Huaixiang
on my own.
Can you not treat me like an outsider?
It's all right if it was somewhere else.
But Huaixiang…
makes me worry.
What do you mean?
Our family used to have
a store in Huaixiang.
After the new magistrate took office…
Tax inspection!
Your store didn't pay anything
for occupancy tax last month.
What's the matter?
Does the Ye family wish to rebel
in the Huaixiang territory?
Sir,
our occupancy and passing taxes
were all paid together.
Well, we still have
the tax receipts that you gave to us.
Hold on, sir. I'll get it for you now.
How dare you forge tax receipts?
It seems like you'd like us
to cuff you up today, right?
Come. Cuff him and take him away.
Sir!
I'll pay those taxes right now.
It was such a calm, peaceful region,
but now it's all rotten and corrupted.
That was why our business couldn't go on.
We withdrew the business.
Now that you're going there,
I must accompany you no matter what.
Jia'er shouldn't go either. I'll go.
Uncle Mingyu, how can you eavesdrop on us?
If I weren't eavesdropping,
I wouldn't even know
that one dares to go alone and the other
is following to cause trouble.
Do not underestimate me. I'm going.
You'd better just stay at home.
Although I couldn't keep my escort agency,
my escort skills are still sound.
I can protect Jiang Li,
but if you're going too
and something happens,
- who should I save?
- You…
Jia'er,
you should stay here.
I don't know
how to explain properly this
to Uncle Mingxuan and Aunt Zhuo.
You have to help me.
All right. Leave the family to me.
If you need anything there, just tell me.
Huaixiang is not far away.
I'll go help at once.
All right.
Then let me say thank you first.
We found it, my lord.
Sure enough, it's a sand gold mine.
I walked down the waterway
in East Mountain
and saw it within three miles of walking.
Is it not secluded at all?
Not really.
They are working in the name
of mining soil and sand.
During the day, it seemed
to be just digging soil and sand.
But the worksheds are cleverly designed.
They were scattered along the river.
The very first workshed
is right next
to the sealed imperial gold mine.
Guess what?
The mine cave is open.
So they are not just digging for sand gold
but also mining imperial gold mines.
But that's impossible.
Forget about open-pit mining
of sand gold, but to open up new mines…
Do they have that many laborers?
Where is the imperial gold mine?
In Huaixiang.
Huaixiang?
Are you surprised?
Xue Huaiyuan,
who was jailed for corruption,
used to be the magistrate there.
What a coincidence.
When was the soil and sand mine built?
About half a year ago.
Six months ago,
Xue Huaiyuan was imprisoned
and the sand mine was built.
Are you saying this has something
to do with the Xue family?
They can mine sand gold themselves.
But those in the capital can't reach
the Huaixiang local government office
to mine the sealed imperial gold mine
in the territorial borders of Huaixiang.
What's so difficult about that?
If they can't reach it, just buy them off.
Didn't that darn governor of Luyang
suck up to them so much?
What if they can't buy him off?
Then just…
Do you mean
Li Zhongnan framed Xue Huaiyuan
to embezzle
from the imperial gold mine?
I'm afraid the deaths
of Xue Fangfei and Xue Zhao
were not solely caused
by offending Wanning.
They were afraid that Xue Huaiyuan
would tell his children about this,
so they silenced both of them.
It seems like I need to go to Huaixiang.
My lord,
you're suddenly going to Huaixiang.
Do you need to inform Ms. Jiang first?
Must I report my whereabouts to anyone?
But it's actually fine to tell her.
HUAIXIANG
Pity us.
Give us some food.
Do a good deed.
LU'S FRUIT PRESERVES
FOR RENT, COME IN FOR FURTHER INQUIRIES
Father, I want to eat this.
Dried fruit preserves!
Sure.
Fragrance sachets!
- Pick one.
- Sir.
- See what you want.
- Which one looks better?
I want to eat this.
You want this one?
HUAIXIANG PRIVATE SCHOOL
All right.
- I'll--
- I want this one.
- I want one!
Kids, come back!
Come back to class!
Kids.
Listen to the teacher.
Go back to class now.
After class,
I will buy you treats, all right?
- All right!
- All right.
- All right. Go.
- Thank you, Mr. Xue.
Time for class!
Eat sweets after school.
Come back.
Come on.
Time for class.
Hurry up.
LI RESIDENCE
Go! Stay away!
What happened to Huaixiang
in the past six months?
SIFANG GUEST HOUSE
Let's stay here.
Place your bets!
Come on, one, two, three! Six, small!
Sir!
- Coming.
- Sir.
Isn't this a guest house?
Why is it like a gambler's den?
Outsider,
you'd better not say that.
These bookmakers are all
from the government office.
Place your bets!
Eleven, big!
I'm done here!
- Don't go.
- Where are you going? Continue playing.
I'm out of money. I really have no money.
Don't you have a house deed?
You can mortgage it.
No money? What are you doing here then?
You have no money?
You can't do anything.
This happens every day.
Can you meddle daily?
Fine. I want two rooms.
That would be ten taels.
Ten taels?
Why don't you just rob people?
I have to pay 70% to the officials.
Otherwise, I can't even run my business.
I…
Let's go.
I know a place.
We can surely find somewhere quieter.
Look at these kids running.
How fresh this is. Bring some home.
Is there a guest house here?
Uncle Mingyu,
the courtyard across the bridge
should be empty.
Go and ask them.
See if we can stay there for a while.
How did you know that?
I'm just guessing.
Come on, Shun.
SEALED BY HUAIXIANG GOVERNMENT OFFICE
ON MARCH, TWELFTH YEAR OF HONGXIAO
Ms. Xue, I got this gift for you.
It's my heartfelt sentiment.
Please accept it.
All right.
You're peeping again.
Shut up.
I have to see which boy
Xue Li fancies.
I've watched Xue Li grow up
since she was a child.
Now and then,
people are coming to propose to her,
yet Xue Li rejects all of them.
- What kind of a person does she like?
- Is that your business?
Madam Chunfang.
Xue Li.
Thank you, Xue Li.
Madam,
may I ask why this residence is sealed?
I have no ill intentions.
I only want to ask
about Magistrate Xue and his family…
Get in now.
You guessed correctly.
There is a spare room to stay up ahead.
Shun, go and clean up first.
Yes, my lady.
Unload all the luggage from the boat.
- All right.
- Go.
Let's go to the government office.
Why are we going there?
The Huaixiang today
is completely different from what I…
Different from what my friend described.
A problem has its root cause.
I'd like to see
what kind of person
is governing here.
But if we go to the government office
right after we arrive,
won't that alert them?
I must trouble you then.
Place your bets now!
Go away!
Who is this?
You're such an eyesore here.
Sir,
everyone can place their bets.
Why are you meddling with their affairs?
I'll bet more than him.
Come on! Come and bet!
- Place your bet!
- Quiet!
Watch and learn.
You're looking for trouble!
Come at me, tough guy.
Take him down!
Look, you broke so many things
and hurt so many of my men.
Take him back and punish him well!
HUAIXIANG GOVERNMENT OFFICE
How can that old drum
still make any sound?
Who's that? He keeps hitting it.
FENG YUTANG
He disturbed my sleep.
Hold him down first
and give him 20 floggings.
PEOPLE'S SAFETY BRINGS BENEFITS
Isn't this Xue…
Magistrate Feng,
I'm the daughter of the Chief Secretariat
and Grand Preceptor,
Jiang Li.
You are obviously the daughter
of a convicted official.
How dare you pretend to be
an imperial court official's daughter?
Guards, arrest her.
How presumptuous!
If you dare to touch me,
you will die.
Magistrate Feng,
you'd better think it through.
You are betting your life
with me today.
You have no qualms
about torturing ordinary, powerless women.
But if you dare slander the daughter
of the Chief Secretariat,
you'll die without a grave to your name.
Are you really--
I don't know who you think I am,
but my father is the Chief Secretariat.
If any harm comes my way,
the entire Huaixiang will pay.
That'll be the end
for a seventh-rank official like you too.
I didn't know people
could look alike to this extent.
Pardon my ignorance.
Please forgive me, Ms. Jiang Li.
May I know why you are here?
Can I help you in any way?
You detained my people.
What happened?
It's that guy who caused trouble
in the gambling den.
Gambling den?
- Magistrate.
- Gambling den?
We don't have brothels and gambling dens.
Huaixiang is an honest place.
The one who caused trouble
at the guest house.
I know of that person.
He is quite overbearing.
He destroyed the entire guest house.
But since you came to get him,
we have to hand him over.
For sure.
But since he destroyed the guest house,
it'd be a little too unreasonable
if there's no form of compensation.
So…
Tong'er.
I didn't expect you to be
so considerate of your people.
- You really are a good official.
- Take it.
I have to.
As the local magistrate,
all I worry about every day
is the affairs of the people.
Go and let him out.
Since you're visiting Huaixiang,
why did you not tell me in advance?
Our place is small.
Sorry for not entertaining you well.
How about this?
What are your plans next?
I can cover all the expenses.
No need for that.
I came to learn to do business
from my uncle.
I didn't ask for my father's help,
so there is no need for you
to make arrangements for me.
Great. That's great.
You're a person of nobility,
yet you keep improving yourself.
You are a role model to all of us.
What about you guys?
Come here.
Look at your way of making money!
These are all new officers
who need straightening out.
Magistrate.
Ms. Jiang Li, I'm so sorry.
People who work in the government office
are rash.
Don't you use your head?
It just so happens that I am new here,
so I can't control them well.
Well…
Uncle Mingyu,
since it's all right now,
we'd better get going.
Thank you, Magistrate Feng.
Hold on.
Ms. Jiang Li, if you need any help,
tell me at once.
I will take care of it for you.
Thank you.
Keep a tight eye on them for me.
People who work in the government office
are rash.
Don't you use your head?
In the past six months,
one of their greatest pleasures
was to torture Magistrate Xue.
Why don't you watch where you're going?
Are you all right, ma'am?
Subtitle translation by: